Guide to the Fales Manuscript Collection circa 1700-2000 MSS.001
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Letter sized boxes, 47643
  - Bindloss, Harold, undated; 51709 (Box 19, Folder 3a)
  - Binyon, Lawrence (1869-1943), undated; 51708 (Box 19, Folder 3b)
  - Birbeck, George (1776-1841), undated; 51707 (Box 19, Folder 4a)
  - Birney, Hoffman, undated; 51706 (Box 19, Folder 4b)
  - Birrell, Augustine (1850-1933), undated; 51705 (Box 19, Folder 4c)
  - Bishop, Henry Healsall, undated; 51704 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Bishop, Henry Rowley (1786-1855), undated; 51703 (Box 19, Folder 6a)
  - Bishop, Morris, undated; 51702 (Box 19, Folder 6b)
  - Bispham, David Scull (1857-1921), undated; 51701 (Box 19, Folder 6c)
  - Black, Robert (1829-1915): 14 letters, undated; 51700 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Black, William (1841-1898): 54 letters, 1 MS. (5pp.); 1 photograph, 1865-1898; undated; 51699 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Blackburn, Paul: MS. At the Well [2pp. TSS.], undated; 51698 (Box 19, Folder 9a)
  - Blackburn, Paul: MS. Here They Go [2pp. TS.(c)], undated; 51697 (Box 19, Folder 9b)
  - Blackburn, Paul: MS. It Might as Well Be Spring [1p. TS.(c)], undated; 51696 (Box 19, Folder 9c)
  - Blackburn, Paul: MS. On the Rocks [2pp. TSS. - to Clayton Eshleman], undated; 51695 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Blackburn, Paul: MS. 1962: Lent Begins with Difficulty [1p. TS.(c)], undated; 51694 (Box 19, Folder 9e)
  - Blackburn, Paul: MS. [no title][1p. TS.(c)], undated; 51693 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Blackburn, Paul: MS. The Reality Invokes [1p. TS.(c)], undated; 51692 (Box 19, Folder 9g)
  - Blackburn, Paul: MS. Sensemaya´ [12pp. TS.(c)], undated; 51691 (Box 19, Folder 9h)
  - Blackburn, Paul: MS. Tequila [4pp. TSS]: P.B. and C. Eshleman, undated; 51690 (Box 19, Folder 9i)
  - Blackburn, Paul: MS. We Live Regular... [2pp. TS.(c)], undated; 51689 (Box 19, Folder 9j)
  - Blackburn, Paul: MS. What Elsie is New [2pp. TS.(c)], undated; 51688 (Box 19, Folder 9k)
  - Blackie, John Stuart (1809-1895): 3 letters, undated; 51687 (Box 19, Folder 10a)
  - Blackwood, Algernon (1869-1951):, 1908-1948; undated; 51686 (Box 19, Folder 10b)
  - Blackwood, William (1776-1834), undated; 51685 (Box 19, Folder 10c)
  - Blackwood, William (ca. 1878), undated; 51684 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Blades, William (1824-1890), undated; 51683 (Box 19, Folder 10e)
  - Blaine, James G. (1830-1893), undated; 51682 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Blair, Emily (1877- ), undated; 51681 (Box 19, Folder 10g)
  - Blair, Hugh (1718-1800), undated; 51680 (Box 19, Folder 10h)
  - Blakemore, Richard Doddridge (1825-1900):, 1860-1881; 51679 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Blakemore, Richard Doddridge (1825-1900): [see also Oversize "B" letter, March 6, 1890, "My dear cousin..."], 1882-1890; 51678 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Blakemore Family: Richard Doddridge, Mrs. Lucy and Eva, undated; 51677 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Blakewell, H., undated; 51676 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Blakewell, Richard S., undated; 51675 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Blakey, Robert (1795-1878), undated; 51674 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Blanchard, Samuel L. (1804-1845), undated; 51673 (Box 19, Folder 17a)
  - Blasco-Ibanez, Vincente (1867-1928), undated; 51672 (Box 19, Folder 17b)
  - Blessington, Marguerite (Power) Countess (1789-1849): [see also Oversize], 1825-1846; undated; 51671 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Blind, Karl (1826-1907), undated; 51670 (Box 19, Folder 19a)
  - Bliss, Arthur, Sir (1891- ), undated; 51669 (Box 19, Folder 19b)
  - Bliss, Geoffrey, undated; 51668 (Box 19, Folder 19c)
  - Blone¨t, Paul (1848-1903) (Max O'Rell, pseud.), undated; 51667 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Blunden, Edmund Charles (1896-1974): 21 letters, 9 pc [1921-1960], 51666 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Blunt, Wifred Scawen, undated; 51665 (Box 19.5, Folder 1a)
  - Boardman, Joseph, undated; 51664 (Box 19.5, Folder 1b)
  - Boardman, William J., undated; 51663 (Box 19.5, Folder 1c)
  - Bobbe, Dorothie (DeBear), undated; 51662 (Box 19.5, Folder 1)
  - Bogan, Louise, undated; 51661 (Box 19.5, Folder 1e)
  - Bogg, Marie, undated; 51660 (Box 19.5, Folder 1)
  - Bojer, Johan, undated; 51659 (Box 19.5, Folder 1g)
  - Bok, Edward William, undated; 51658 (Box 19.5, Folder 1h)
  - Boker, George Henry, undated; 51657 (Box 19.5, Folder 1i)
  - Bonaparte Family: Napoleon I; Napoleon III, 1 envelope; Bonaparte, Jerome, 1 letter; Bonaparte, Joseph, 1 letter; Bonaparte, Lucien; Walewski, Alexander, 1 letter, undated; 51656 (Box 19.5, Folder 2)
  - Bone, James, undated; 51655 (Box 19.5, Folder 3a)
  - Bone, Muirhead, undated; 51654 (Box 19.5, Folder 3b)
  - Bonnaire, H., undated; 51653 (Box 19.5, Folder 3c)
  - Bonsal, Stephen (1865-1951), undated; 51652 (Box 19.5, Folder 3)
  - Bonsels, Waldemar (1880 or 81-1952), undated; 51651 (Box 19.5, Folder 3e)
  - Boone, Daniel, undated; 51650 (Box 19.5, Folder 3)
  - Boothby, Brooke, Sir (1743-1824), undated; 51649 (Box 19.5, Folder 3g)
  - Boothby, Guy Newell (1867-1905), undated; 51648 (Box 19.5, Folder 3h)
  - Borleau, Ethel Mary (1882-1942), undated; 51647 (Box 19.5, Folder 3i)
  - Boroff, David, undated; 51646 (Box 19.5, Folder 3j)
  - Borrow, George Henry (1803-1881): A.L.s.: to George Petrie, 1859; 51645 (Box 20, Folder 1a)
  - Borrow, George Henry (1803-1881): A.L.s.: to The Highland Society, Apr 4, 1830; 51644 (Box 20, Folder 1b)
  - Borrow, George Henry (1803-1881): A.L.s.: 4 pieces, undated; 51643 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Borrow, George Henry (1803-1881): MS.; 7 pieces, 1 note, 1 signature, undated; 51642 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Borrow, George Henry (1803-1881): MS. Gypsey Luke (1835-36 on title page), ca.1870; 51641 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Borrow, George Henry (1803-1881): MS. May Day, undated; 51640 (Box 20, Folder 5a)
  - Borrow, George Henry (1803-1881): MS. The History of Jack with the Bear's Ear, undated; 51639 (Box 20, Folder 5b)
  - Borrow, George Henry (1803-1881): The History of Bluebeard, translated into the Turkish Language, undated; 51638 (Box 20, Folder 5c)
  - Borrow, George Henry (1803-1881): The Story of Yuashka with the Bear's Ear - published version in Once a Week, undated; 51637 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Borrow, George Henry (1803-1881): MS. Romantic Ballads [portion of MS.], 1826; 51636 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Borrow, George Henry (1803-1881): MS. Sundry Examples, undated; 51635 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Borrow, George Henry (1803-1881): MS. Targum, 1835; 51634 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Borrow, George Henry (1803-1881): MS. Wild Wales [fragment], undated; 51633 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Borrow, George Henry (1803-1881): Addenda, Correspondence, etc., undated; 51632 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Boswell, James (1740-1795): 1 Inscription, undated; 51631 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Botta Vincenzo (1818-1894), undated; 51630 (Box 21, Folder 2a)
  - Bottome, Phyllis, undated; 51629 (Box 21, Folder 2b)
  - Bottomley, Gordon (1874-1948), undated; 51628 (Box 21, Folder 2c)
  - Boucicault, Dion (1820-1890): 2 letters, 1 MS. (4pp), undated; 51627 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Boughton, George Henry (1833-1905), undated; 51626 (Box 21, Folder 4a)
  - Boulger, Theodora (1847-1889), undated; 51625 (Box 21, Folder 4b)
  - Bourget, Paul Charles Joseph (1852-1935), undated; 51624 (Box 21, Folder 4c)
  - Bouton, Elisa J. Nesmith (Mrs. John Bell), undated; 51623 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Bouton, John Bell (1830-1902), undated; 51622 (Box 21, Folder 4e)
  - Bowen, Catherine Drinker, undated; 51621 (Box 21, Folder 5a)
  - Bowen, Elizabeth, undated; 51620 (Box 21, Folder 5b)
  - Bower, Marian, undated; 51619 (Box 21, Folder 6a)
  - Bowles, Emily, 1908; 266946 (Box 21, Folder 6a1)
  - Bowles, Paul: Correspondence to Richard Goldstone [gift of R.G.]: 18 A.L.s., 11 T.L.s., 1 P.C.s, undated; 51618 (Box 21, Folder 6b)
  - Bowles, Thomas, undated; 51617 (Box 21, Folder 6c)
  - Bowles, William Lisle (1762-1850), undated; 51616 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Bowring, Deborah, Lady, undated; 51615 (Box 21, Folder 6e)
  - Bowring, J., undated; 51614 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Bowring, John, Sir (1792-1872), undated; 51613 (Box 21, Folder 6g)
  - Boyd, Thomas, undated; 51612 (Box 21, Folder 7a)
  - Boyd, William, undated; 51611 (Box 21, Folder 7b)
  - Boyle, Kay: MS. Two Twilights, undated; 51610 (Box 21, Folder 7c)
  - Braddon, M. E. (Mary Elizabeth) (1835-1915) (also, Maxwell, Mary Elizabeth Braddon), undated; 51609 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Bradford, Gamaliel (1863-1932), undated; 51608 (Box 21, Folder 9a)
  - Bradford, Richard, undated; 51607 (Box 21, Folder 9b)
  - Bradford, Roark, undated; 51606 (Box 21, Folder 9c)
  - Bradley, Edward (1827-1889) (Cuthbert Bede, pseud.): 15 letters, 2 envelopes, 1 MS. Spring Tide, undated; 51605 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Brady, Cyrus Townsend (1861-1920): 6 letters (12 pages) [see also Oversize for MSS.], undated; 51604 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Bragdon, Claude, undated; 51603 (Box 21, Folder 12a)
  - Bray, Anna Eliza (Kempe) (1790-1883), undated; 51602 (Box 21, Folder 12b)
  - Braybrooke, C., undated; 51601 (Box 21, Folder 12c)
  - Brett, George P., undated; 51600 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Brenil, Henri (1877-1961), undated; 51599 (Box 21, Folder 12e)
  - Brewster, William (1851-1919), undated; 51598 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Bridge, James Howard (1858-1939), undated; 51597 (Box 21, Folder 13a)
  - Bridges, Robert Seymour (1844-1930), undated; 51596 (Box 21, Folder 13b)
  - Bridgman, Herbert Lawrence & Mrs., undated; 51595 (Box 21, Folder 13c)
  - Bridgman, Laura, undated; 51594 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Bright, John (1811-1889), undated; 51593 (Box 21, Folder 14a)
  - Brinkley, Frank (1841-1912), undated; 51592 (Box 21, Folder 14b)
  - Brinton, Daniel Garrison (1837-1899), undated; 51591 (Box 21, Folder 14c)
  - Brittain, T., undated; 51590 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Britton, John (1771-1857), undated; 51589 (Box 21, Folder 14e)
  - Brodie, Benjamin Collins, Sir (1783-1862), undated; 51588 (Box 21, Folder 15a)
  - Brodkey, Harold: TS. Angel, undated; 51587 (Box 21, Folder 15b)
  - Bromfield, Louis (1846-1956), undated; 51586 (Box 21, Folder 15c)
  - Bronte¨, Charlotte (1816-1855), undated; 51585 (Box 21, Folder 16a)
  - Bronte¨, Patrick (1777-1861), undated; 51584 (Box 21, Folder 16b)
  - Brooke, Frances (Moore) (1724-1789), undated; 51583 (Box 21, Folder 17a)
  - Brooke, Stopford Augustus (1832-1916), undated; 51582 (Box 21, Folder 17b)
  - Brooks, Charles William Shirley (1816-1874), undated; 51581 (Box 21, Folder 17c)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck (1886-1963), undated; 51580 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Brophy, John (1899- ), undated; 51579 (Box 21, Folder 18a)
  - Brotherton, Alice Williams (? -1930), undated; 51578 (Box 21, Folder 18b)
  - Brough, Fanny (1854-1914), undated; 51577 (Box 21, Folder 18c)
  - Brougham and Voux, Henry (1778-1868), undated; 51576 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Broughton, Rhoda (1840-1920), undated; 51575 (Box 21, Folder 18e)
  - Broughton, Richard, undated; 51574 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Brown, Alice (1857-1948), undated; 51573 (Box 21, Folder 19a)
  - Brown, David Paul (1795-1872), undated; 51572 (Box 21, Folder 19b)
  - Brown, Ford Maddox (1821-1893), undated; 51571 (Box 21, Folder 19c)
  - Brown, George MacKay: MS. [1 of 2] The Year of the Whale, undated; 51570 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Brown, George MacKay: MS. [2 of 2] The Year of the Whale, undated; 51569 (Box 21.5, Folder 1)
  - Brown, Horatio Robert Forbes (1854-1926), undated; 51568 (Box 21.5, Folder 2a)
  - Brown, John (1810-1882), undated; 51567 (Box 21.5, Folder 2b)
  - Brown, Katherine Holland (d.1931), undated; 51566 (Box 21.5, Folder 2c)
  - Brown, Robert (1773-1858), undated; 51565 (Box 21.5, Folder 2)
  - Brown, William F. (Bishop of Pella), undated; 51564 (Box 21.5, Folder 2e)
  - Brown, William Lawrence (1755-1830), undated; 51563 (Box 21.5, Folder 2)
  - Browne, Hablot Knight (1815-1882): 2 letters, 2 drawings [see also Dickens file for 1. drawing of C.D., 2. Illustration for David Copperfield], undated; 51562 (Box 21.5, Folder 3)
  - Browning, Elizabeth Barrett (1806-1861), undated; 51561 (Box 21.5, Folder 4a)
  - Browning, Oscar (1837-1923), undated; 51560 (Box 21.5, Folder 4b)
  - Browning, Robert (1812-1889), undated; 51559 (Box 21.5, Folder 4c)
  - Browning, Sarianna (1814-1903), undated; 51558 (Box 21.5, Folder 4)
  - Brownson, Orestes Augustus (1803-1876), undated; 51557 (Box 21.5, Folder 5)
  - Bruton, H. W.: 2 A.L.s. to, 1 A.L.s. from Charles Dickens, undated; 51556 (Box 21.5, Folder 6)
  - Bryant, Jacob: 1 A.L.s., undated; 51555 (Box 21.5, Folder 7)
  - Bryant, William Cullen (1794-1898): 14 letters, 6 miscellaneous, 1 photo and autograph [see also Oversize for 1 letter], undated; 51554 (Box 21.5, Folder 8)
  - Bryce, James Bryce, Viscount (1838-1922), undated; 51553 (Box 22, Folder 1a)
  - Brydges, Samuel Egerton, Sir (1762-1837), undated; 51552 (Box 22, Folder 1b)
  - Brydone, Patrick (1743-1818), undated; 51551 (Box 22, Folder 1c)
  - Bryson, Charles (1877- ) (Charles Barry, pseud.), undated; 51550 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Buccleuch, Walter Francis Montagu-Douglas-Scott (1806-1884), undated; 51549 (Box 22, Folder 1e)
  - Buchan, John (1875-1940), undated; 51548 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Buchanan, George, undated; 51547 (Box 22, Folder 3a)
  - Buchanan, Robert Williams (1841-1901), undated; 51546 (Box 22, Folder 3b)
  - Buchanan, Scott Milross (1895-1968), undated; 51545 (Box 22, Folder 3c)
  - Buchanan, Thompson (1877-1937), undated; 51544 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Buck, Horace H. C., undated; 51543 (Box 22, Folder 4a)
  - Buck, Pearl (Sydenstricker), undated; 51542 (Box 22, Folder 4b)
  - Buckingham, James Silk (1786-1855), undated; 51541 (Box 22, Folder 5a)
  - Buckle, George Earl (1854-1935), undated; 51540 (Box 22, Folder 5b)
  - Buckley, Anne P.: Diary 1853, undated; 51539 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Budge, Ernest A. T. W., Sir (1857-1934), undated; 51538 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Bukowsky, Charles: 8 T.L.s. [to Carl Weissner], 2 envelopes [1972], 51537 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Bulfinch, Thomas (1796-1867), undated; 51536 (Box 22, Folder 9a)
  - Bullen, Frank Thomas (1837-1915), undated; 51535 (Box 22, Folder 9b)
  - Bullen, Frank Thomas (1837-1915): MS. The Bengal Pilot Service, undated; 51534 (Box 22, Folder 10a)
  - Bullen, Frank: MS. Cut Off from the World [Chapters I-XI], undated; 51533 (Box 22, Folder 10b)
  - Bullen, Frank: MS. Cut Off from the World [Chapters XII-], undated; 51532 (Box 22, Folder 10c)
  - Bullen, Frank: Havana in 1870 [corrected galley], undated; 51531 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Bullett, Gerald William (1844- ), undated; 51530 (Box 22, Folder 11a)
  - Bulloch, John Malcolm (1867- ), undated; 51529 (Box 22, Folder 11b)
  - Bunche, Ralph Johnson, undated; 51528 (Box 22, Folder 11c)
  - Bunner, Henry Cuyler (1855-1896), undated; 51527 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Bunting, Mary Ingraham (1910-1998), undated; 51526 (Box 22, Folder 11e)
  - Burch, Claire: 1 T.L.s., undated; 51525 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Burchett, Josiah (1666-1746) [see also Oversize], undated; 51524 (Box 22, Folder 12a)
  - Burder, George (1752-1832), undated; 51523 (Box 22, Folder 12b)
  - Burgess, Gelett (1866-1951): 4 MSS., undated; 51522 (Box 22.5, Folder 1)
  - Burgess, Thornton Waldo (1874-), undated; 51521 (Box 22.5, Folder 2a)
  - Burgin, George Brown (1856- ), undated; 51520 (Box 22.5, Folder 2b)
  - Burham, Clara Louise (Root) (1854-1927), undated; 51519 (Box 22.5, Folder 2c)
  - Burke, John Bernard, Sir (1814-1892), undated; 51518 (Box 22.5, Folder 2)
  - Burlingaine, Edward Livermore (1848-1920), undated; 51517 (Box 22.5, Folder 2e)
  - Burnand, Francis Cowley (1836-1917), undated; 51516 (Box 22.5, Folder 2)
  - Burne-Jones, Edward, Sir (1833-1898), undated; 51515 (Box 22.5, Folder 3a)
  - Burne-Jones, Georgiana (1840-1920), undated; 51514 (Box 22.5, Folder 3b)
  - Burnett, Dana, undated; 51513 (Box 22.5, Folder 4)
  - Burnett, Frances Hodgson (1849-1924): 6 letters, 1 will, 2 autographs, 1 envelope, undated; 51512 (Box 22.5, Folder 5)
  - Burnett, Henry (Dickens's brother-in-law): 8 letters, undated; 51511 (Box 22.5, Folder 6)
  - Burney, Sarah Harriet (1772-1844), undated; 51510 (Box 22.5, Folder 7a)
  - Burns, John (1850-1943), undated; 51509 (Box 22.5, Folder 7b)
  - Burns, Robert (1759-1796): [see also Oversize] 2 letters from Isabella Burns Begg to Rev. Olver, 1 death notice of Mrs. Jean Armour, undated; 51508 (Box 22.5, Folder 8)
  - [Burns, Robert (1759-1796)]: Burns and Clarinda: [Clarinda refused to allow the publication of her letters], undated; 51507 (Box 22.5, Folder 9)
  - Burroughs, John (1837-1921): 28 letters [see also box 23], undated; 51506 (Box 22.5, Folder 10)
  - Burroughs, John (1837-1921): MS. Concerning the Development of Living Forms [see also box 23], undated; 51505 (Box 22.5, Folder 11a)
  - Burroughs, John (1837-1921): MS. God and Man's Relation to Nature, undated; 51504 (Box 22.5, Folder 11b)
  - Burroughs, John (1837-1921): MS. Life and Chance [2 copies], undated; 51503 (Box 22.5, Folder 11c)
  - Burroughs, John (1837-1921): MS. The New Materialism, undated; 51502 (Box 22.5, Folder 11)
  - Burroughs, John (1837-1921): MS. Physics, undated; 51501 (Box 22.5, Folder 11e)
  - Burroughs, John (1837-1921): MS. The Round World, undated; 51500 (Box 22.5, Folder 11)
  - Burroughs, John (1837-1921): MS. The Stars Come Nightly, undated; 51499 (Box 23, Folder 1a)
  - Burroughs, John (1837-1921): MS. The Still Small Voice, undated; 51498 (Box 23, Folder 1b)
  - Burroughs, John (1837-1921): MS. Tracks in the Snow, undated; 51497 (Box 23, Folder 1c)
  - Burroughs, John (1837-1921): MS. The Triumph of Good over Evil, undated; 51496 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Burroughs, John (1837-1921): MS. Unused Material on Vital versus Mechanistic Conception of Life, undated; 51495 (Box 23, Folder 1e)
  - Burroughs, John (1837-1921): MS. Waiting, undated; 51494 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Burroughs, John (1837-1921): MS. Whence Comes the Force, undated; 51493 (Box 23, Folder 1g)
  - Burroughs, John (1837-1921): MS. Fragments, undated; 51492 (Box 23, Folder 1h)
  - Burroughs, John (1837-1921): MS. Untitled - 6 pieces, undated; 51491 (Box 23, Folder 1i)
  - Burroughs, William S. (Seward) (1914-1997): 1 letter, undated; 51490 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Burrows, Montagu (1819-1905), undated; 51489 (Box 23, Folder 3a)
  - Burton, Richard (1861-1940), undated; 51488 (Box 23, Folder 3b)
  - Bury, Adrian, undated; 51487 (Box 23, Folder 3c)
  - Bury, Charlotte, Lady (1775-1861), undated; 51486 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Bus Fare (Aram Saroyan), undated; 51485 (Box 23, Folder 3e)
  - Butler, Charles (1750-1832), undated; 51484 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Butler, Ellis Parker (1869-1937), undated; 51483 (Box 23, Folder 3g)
  - Butler, S., undated; 51482 (Box 23, Folder 3h)
  - Butler, Samuel (1835-1902): 4 letters; 1 letter (Jos. B. Fort), undated; 51481 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Butler, William, undated; 51480 (Box 23, Folder 5a)
  - Butler, William Allen (1825-1902), undated; 51479 (Box 23, Folder 5b)
  - Butterick, George, undated; 51478 (Box 23, Folder 5c)
  - Butterworth, Hezekiah (1839-1905), undated; 51477 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Butts, Mary (1892-1937), undated; 51476 (Box 23, Folder 5e)
  - Buxton, Thomas Fowell, Sir (1786-1845), undated; 51475 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Bynner, Witter (1881-1968): 8 letters, 1 P.C., 3 MSS., 1 letter (Henriette), 1 envelope, 1 photograph (signed), undated; 51474 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Byrne, Donn (1889-1928): 1 letter, 1 signature, undated; 51473 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Byron, Anne Isabella (Milbanke) Byron (1792-1860): 6 letters, 1 MS., 1 photograph, undated; 51472 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Byron, Catherine (Gordon) (1765-1811): 3 drafts, undated; 51471 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Byron, George Gordon Noe¨l Byron, 6th Baron (1788-1824): 3 letters, 2 envelopes, 1 MS.; Barff-- 1 letter, undated; 51470 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Byron, George Gordon Noe¨l Byron, 6th Baron (1788-1824): Pictorial, undated; 51469 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Byron, Henry James (1834-1884), undated; 51468 (Box 23, Folder 12a)
  - Bryon, William, 4th Lord (1669-1736), undated; 51467 (Box 23, Folder 12b)
  - Cabell, James Branch (1879-1958): 7 letters, undated; 51466 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Cable, George Washington (1844-1925): 15 pieces, 1 envelope, 1883-1909; 51465 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Cabot, Carolyn Sturgis (Channing) (1846-1905): 1 MS. A Child's Recollection of Thomas Wentworth Higginson, undated; 51464 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Cadell, Thomas (1773-1836), undated; 51463 (Box 23, Folder 16a)
  - [Caine, Hall, Sir: see Boxes 24 and 25], 1690-2000; 51462 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_bf9f782baf0c97005c03c736ee33edb3)
  - Caird, Edward (1835-1908), undated; 51461 (Box 23, Folder 16b)
  - Caldecott, Randolph (1846-1886), undated; 51460 (Box 23, Folder 16c)
  - Caldwell, Erskine (1903-1987): 26 T.L.s. [to/from NAL], 1 T.L.s. to F. W. Dupee (in The Miscellany) [1930], 1 T.L.s. to Stanley Rinehart [1940], 1 T.L.s. [1947?], [24 NAL letters not to be seen without NAL permission], 1930, 1940, 1947, 1959-61; 51459 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Caldwell, Erskine (1903-1987): 2 Manuscript Lists; MS. From Tobacco Road, undated; 51458 (Box 23, Folder 18a)
  - Caldwell, Erskine (1903-1987): MS. Picking Cotton, undated; 51457 (Box 23, Folder 18b)
  - Caldwell, Erskine (1903-1987): MS. 13 Short Stories, undated; 51456 (Box 23, Folder 18c)
  - Caldwell, Erskine (1903-1987): MS. 7 TS.s. Short Stories, undated; 51455 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Caine, Hall, Sir (1853-1931):, 1879-1890; 51454 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Caine, Hall, Sir (1853-1931):, 1891-1900; 51453 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Caine, Hall, Sir (1853-1931):, 1901-1910; 51452 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Caine, Hall, Sir (1853-1931):, 1911-1920; 51451 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Caine, Hall, Sir (1853-1931):, 1920-1928; 51450 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Caine, Hall, Sir (1853-1931), undated; 51449 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Caine, Hall, Sir (1853-1931): MSS., etc., undated; 51448 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Caine, Hall, Sir (1853-1931): Album, undated; 51447 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Callahan, North: MS. Flight from the Republic (1)[Chapters 1-3], undated; 51446 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Callahan, North: MS. Flight from the Republic (2)[Chapters 4- ], undated; 51445 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Callahan, North: MS. Flight from the Republic (3)[Index], undated; 51444 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Calmour, Alfred Cecil: 1 letter, undated; 51443 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Campbell, Thomas (1777-1844): 11 letters, 2 MSS. [see also Oversize], undated; 51442 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Canfield, Mary Cass, undated; 51441 (Box 26, Folder 6a)
  - Canning, George (1770-1827), undated; 51440 (Box 26, Folder 6b)
  - Cannon, Gilbert (1884-1955), undated; 51439 (Box 26, Folder 6c)
  - Cant, Thomas, undated; 51438 (Box 26, Folder 7a)
  - Cantuar, A. C., undated; 51437 (Box 26, Folder 7b)
  - Caracciolo, Signor, undated; 51436 (Box 26, Folder 7c)
  - Cargill, Oscar: MS. Eliot [1 of 2]: [unfinished study of T.S. Elliot's Wasteland], undated; 51435 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Cargill, Oscar, undated; 51434 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Cargill, Oscar: MS. Eliot [2 of 2], undated; 51433 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Carleton, William (1794-1869), undated; 51432 (Box 27, Folder 1a)
  - Carleton, Will (1845-1912), undated; 51431 (Box 27, Folder 1b)
  - Carlyle, Thomas (1795-1881): 1 letter, 1 annotated Notes and Queries, undated; 51430 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Carman, Bliss (1861-1929): 6 letters, 1 signature, undated; 51429 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Carmichael, Montgomery, undated; 51428 (Box 27, Folder 4a)
  - Carpenter, Edward (1844-1924), undated; 51427 (Box 27, Folder 4b)
  - [Carroll, Lewis: see Dodgson, Charles Lutwidge, Box 46], 1690-2000; 51426 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_22d5c244f8f7b1dbf34445d468c12b85)
  - Carter, Elizabeth (1717-1806), undated; 51425 (Box 27, Folder 4c)
  - Carter, Frederick, undated; 51424 (Box 27, Folder 5a)
  - Carter, W. H. J., undated; 51423 (Box 27, Folder 5b)
  - Cary -- Cawley: Cary, Alice (1820-1871), 2 letters; [and others], undated; 51422 (Box 27, Folder 6a)
  - Cary, Phoebe (1824-1871), undated; 51421 (Box 27, Folder 6b)